Lesson 1
Spooky Scary Sensei
Keep things simple.
That was the conclusion I had reached
after 16 years on this earth.
Uncomplicated friends.
Uncomplicated classmates.
You could say that the new school
Abikura-kun,
Second Year Student
Follows the principle of
keeping things simple
year was going swimmingly.
Heh heh heh...
All that's left is to hope we get
an uncomplicated homeroom teacher.
Huh? What's that?
A-Are you our teacher?
She's saying something!
It must be some kind of curse!
She's covered in blood, and she's shaking!
That's our homeroom teacher for this year?
That's Hiyori Hiwamura, our teacher.
Since the first day of the new semester,
people started saying
that if you offend her, she'll curse you.
Students are so scared of her that she's ended up
with the moniker, "Spooky Scary Sensei".
I saw Spooky Scary Sensei's notebook,
and it had a bunch of talismans stuck in it!
She tackled me to the ground all of a sudden.
Mutter
She muttered a curse at me...
Before long, there were all sorts of testimonies.
This sucks...
I can't believe someone that creepy
is our homeroom teacher.
This can't be good at all!
P-Peter Piper picked a peck of pickled peppers...
Wha-?!
That's Spooky Scary Sensei, isn't it?
What's she doing in there all on her own?
Cough
Okay...
R-Right!
L-Let's start the class!
Class?
But school's finished for the day.
There aren't any students here.
Wait...
Is she using plushies to represent
the students in some kind of cursed ritual?!
Loooom
She's just like everyone said, after all!
First, we'll review
what you learned in first year.
"Opinion."
Can anyone tell me what this word means?
Yes, Cuttlefish-san!
Point
Cuttlefish?!
I-It means, someone's own impression of something!
Correct!
Correct! Th-That's correct! Gold star!
Sh-She's playing both roles herself?!
Next question!
M-Maybe she really is just practicing
how to teach a class?!
With plushies as students!
Yes, Pufferfish-san!
It means the air or mood around us!
Correct!
Jeez, her voice is way too shaky and quiet!
I suppose my voice is too quiet, huh?
Oh, she realized!
Rub
That's it!
Take a breath deep enough to expand your stomach,
then you'll be able to speak more strongly...
Flash
Huh? What?!
Touch
Why did she strip?!
Oh, was she trying to make it easier
to see her stomach expanding?!
Surely you can understand
without taking your clothes off?
That breathing method's for giving birth!
Wheeze
Jeez, she has no stamina at all!
But, like, wow...
Ba-dump
Huff
She's so weak and wimpy!
Puff
Huff
I can't look away... for various reasons!
Ba-dump
L-Let's take a break for a moment.
Reach
Wait! That chair there... She moved it before!
Watch out!
I... I...
get really bad stage fright and have no stamina...
and I'm clumsy.
Blush
But I was finally able to fulfill my dream
of becoming a teacher.
And even though it's only my first year doing
this, I was able to become a homeroom teacher.
That's why I thought I need to do my best, but...
H-Her voice is getting quieter and quieter!
Peek
This morning I tripped and hit my head
on the door and it made a big noise,
so I ended up scaring everyone...
Oh, that's why she had blood on her?!
Oh, that's right!
I need to check what's next
on the schedule so I don't forget!
Covered
They're not talismans! They're sticky notes?!
The tackle...!
I-I'm sowwy asdfg hjkl!
The curses!
I've solved the mystery!
The person in charge of my class isn't a monster.
Her voice is unsteady, and she has no stamina.
But she's a hard worker...
she's more like a mouse!
O-Okay, I'm gonna head off now.
U-Um... abik ghjkl...
S-Sorry, could you say that again?
Abikura-kun, thank you for helping me just now!
I fell for her hook, line, and sinker.
This is no good!
Since that encounter, I can't help worrying
about that strange teacher of ours.
One, two...
One, two, three... One, two, three...
Hiwamura
Wobble
Hiwamura-sensei?!
Five, six...
Is she trying to do some training
so that she can build up her stamina?
Stretch
But wait, what's up with that tracksuit?!
Puff
Huff
It's so tight on her! It's gotta be
from when she was in high school!
Hiwamura
Haaah
She's already tired
after finishing the warmup exercises!
R-Right! Time to start today's special training!
Special training?
Jump rope?! I see, jump rope is so easy that even
Weak and Wimpy Sensei should
be able to do it without overexerting.
Here goes...
There are people who can't even manage
to jump the rope at all?!
Wrapped tight
She's acting like she finished a whole set...
Let's take a little break.
Wobble
She'll trip if she tries to walk like that!
Look out!
Asd fgh! Abikura-kun! It's not what it looks like!
At this school, they hold
a big jump rope tournament
One
between all the classes
every sports day in October, right?
Two
Since I have a lot less stamina
than the average person,
I wanted to practice for it
so I don't let everyone down...
But it's only April right now!
In that case, I think you'd be better off
sticking with basic exercises.
Like doing strength training at home
or something like that.
I tried, but it didn't exactly... go to plan.
Besides, when I exert myself,
I end up making strange noises,
so I was worried about disturbing my neighbors...
Strange noises?!
Like the ones people thought were curses?
Dfsdfm asfxp weofl.
Oh, but...!
If you'd be willing to help me, Abikura-kun,
I think I might be okay!
Badump
Tremble
How did things end up like this...?!
Dammit... I can't stay calm.
Quick, make small talk!
By the way, Sensei. What's your ideal type?
Why did I just ask her that?!
Let me think.
Someone known to dress smartly,
who has a strong voice and good leadership skills.
Someone who the students can trust.
That's the type of teacher I want to be.
She thought I was talking about teachers!
Reality
Ideal
But, like, that's the exact opposite
of how she is now.
So this was what she meant by strange noises.
Typical Weak and Wimpy Sensei,
even her motor coordination is weak.
Everyone thinks of our homeroom teacher as Spooky
Scary Sensei, but it's just a misunderstanding.
Ah, Spooky... I mean, Hiwamura-sensei.
You dropped one of your notebooks-
Here! I'm sorry!
Kanji Practice Notebook
I know she's just trying to
remember everyone's names,
but does she have to treat it
like kanji practice?
She's been doing her best, but she's so clumsy.
Is there anything I can do to help her?
Hiwamura-sensei?!
She's crying so much. What is she reading?
The author's bio?! What on earth did they write?
Typical Weak and Wimpy Sensei,
she even has weak tear ducts!
Oh, she's buying it.
Since it made her cry that much,
I'm kinda intrigued as to what it is.
How to Get Over Social Anxiety
High School Teaching Techniques
50 methods to help students
reach their best in one year!
Those are the kind of books she's buying?!
Now I'm the one on the verge of tears.
Panic
Does she not have enough money or something?
You've gotta be kidding me!
Typical Weak and Wimpy Sensei,
she's no good at budgeting, either!
Um...
Uhh...
Phew
Oh, thank goodness. She had enough after all.
Do you need a bag? They're five yen.
It was so close that she doesn't
have five yen left over?!
High School Teaching Techniques
50 methods to help students
reach their best in one year!
How to Get Over Social Anxiety
I-I'll be fine!
She would not, in fact, be fine.
Even at the best of times, Weak and Wimpy Sensei
would struggle to get home safely
while carrying three books and an umbrella!
Oh, that's right!
Hiwamura-sensei!
Squish
A-Abikura-kun?! Asdfg hjkl...I'm sowwy!
D-Don't worry, ah, I mean... Sensei!
If you like, please use this!
A bag? Oh gosh, you don't have to...
Sorry it's so flimsy.
But I figured it'd be better than nothing.
Th-Thank you.
You've gotta be kidding me.
Wow!
The bag you gave me protected
my books just in time, Abikura-kun!
My clothes ended up getting wet, though.
I like books. Thank you for protecting them.
Her shirt's gone all see-through!
Sensei, you should probably keep your jacket on...
Typical Weak and Wimpy Sensei,
even her luck is lacking.
Hiwamura-sensei?!
A-Abikura-kun, good... mornngh...
Are you okay? Why're you running?
I'm not a morning person,
so I overslept by accident...
Typical Weak and Wimpy Sensei,
she can't even wake up early.
Peek
Today's second period is my
first long homeroom with everyone,
so I need to get there early
so I can get ready properly...
Be careful... or rather, um your shirt button...
Ah! G-Goo mornngh...
Will she really be able to manage
an entire hour-long homeroom session?
She's enough of a mess in our normal
short homeroom time every day.
O-Okay everyone, the time...
has come...
What, our time has come?! Is that a threat?!
Dread
Here we go again.
Another homeroom session that's dead on arrival.
DEAD ON ARRIVAL...
Shake
She can't even make it one second in.
Everyone's totally freaked out...
Her handwriting's all shaky.
Is she even more nervous than usual?!
What is she writing?! Sutras?!
Is this the start of our own funeral?!
We've gone totally off the rails.
Her face looks pretty red.
Is she still recovering from running this morning?
Ba-dump
Rip
S-Spooky Scary Sensei is...
...holding a box cutter?!
Oh, snap.
Is she charging up for an attack?!
Doom
Glare
Throwing chalk is too tame for
Spooky Scary Sensei! She throws box cutters!
Nah, she can't throw anything
with her noodle arms.
There must be some reason
she's stuck on the floor like that.
It's my first long homeroom with everyone.
Okay! I'll be the class president!
Since it's our first long homeroom
session of the new school year,
that means we need to decide
on our class president, right?
In that case, I'll take it from here...
Aw man, this isn't simple at all!
Are you okay, Sensei?
A-Abikura-kun, um, could you...
help me get free?
Her tights are caught!
She's not wearing panties!
Since I overslept this morning...
I forgot to put them on.
How do you forget THAT?!
Well, I guess I can understand after seeing
how flustered she was this morning.
And now, I've got a cramp in my leg...
But I can't just grab her tights
in front of everyone.
Abikura-kun...
I don't want my first long homeroom session
with everyone to end in failure!
S-Sure, I'll untangle it now.
Flinch
Silence
Twitch
I'll now continue this homeroom session!
Yo, Prez! Will ya do my homework for me?
Not a chance!
I had to do it to help Sensei,
but becoming class president was a huge mistake.
The simple school life I envisioned
is crumbling right before my eyes...
What's this?
Some kinda death threat?!
To Abikura-kun.
I'd like to speak with you
about class operations going forward,
so would you be able to stay behind after school?
Time with Sensei, just the two of us...
I guess being class president
isn't so bad after all!
A-Abikura-kun, thank you for coming.
A megaphone?!
U-Uh, Sensei, I thought we were supposed to be
discussing class operations?
Th-That was my intention,
but at the staff meeting today...
Hiwamura-sensei,
your voice is quite difficult to hear,
doesn't it hinder your ability to teach class?
Shock
She's right on the money, though!
So I thought, if I use this,
everyone should be able to hear me better.
Asd fgh jkl!
She's putting a lot of effort into it,
but she's still inaudible,
even with the megaphone...
I think that's a good idea.
I feel like people are only scared of you because
they don't know what you're trying to say.
Th-They're scared of me?
What?! She hadn't noticed?
The students are scared of me?!
Man, I feel bad for her!
Well, I had noticed that nobody
was willing to look me in the eye...
But wait, you interact with me just fine,
don't you, Abikura-kun?
Huh?! Well, yeah.
Ba-dump
Come to think of it, Abikura-kun,
I heard that you weren't a particularly
assertive student in your first year.
But despite that, you wanted
to volunteer for class president,
so that's how you mustered up
the courage to speak to me, huh?
That's impressive! I really respect that!
Uh-oh, she's getting the wrong idea.
Anyway!
I think using a megaphone is a great idea,
maybe just try to speak a little slower
and make sure you enunciate clearly?
O-Okay...
P-Peter Piper picked a peck of pickled peppers.
That's great! I can hear you!
R-Really?!
Th-Then let's check if you can
hear me from the back
if I stand at the podium up front!
Peter Piper picked...
I can hear you! Loud and clear!
Beaaam
Th-This way people won't be
scared of me anymore, right?!
It'll definitely work!
Do you think my feelings will reach everyone?
They will! I'm sure of it!
Abikura-kun! Are my feelings reaching you?
Ba-dump
They are!
Are we in a soap opera or what?
Thank you.
You're always helping me out,
aren't you, Abikura-kun?
Huh? Oh, shucks, not really...
I just happen to be around
when she's working hard to improve.
I guess I really might like Sensei, after all.
Ba-dump
But, you know, this still tires me out...
Slip
The megaphone!
The precious item that's gonna help
Sensei connect with everyone in class!
S-Sorry, Abikura-kun...
N-No, I'm sorry, too...
Vrrr
Twitch
I-I'll move right away...
Ah don't!
Please don't say anything right now!
We didn't manage to discuss class
operations much in the end, did we?
Well, we'll just try again some other time.
A-Abikura-kun!
You can live your dream of being class president!
Let's do our best together, okay?
Ah, right...
And so, she totally got the wrong idea about me.